#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/joe-dougherty-24a2738 (LinkedIn)

#### Top Skills

Asset Management
Capital
Alternative Investments

# Joe Dougherty

Mutual Fund & Investment Management Executive Dallas/Fort Worth Area

## Summary

Most recently, Mr. Dougherty served as President of Pyxis Capital, L.P. (formerly Highland Funds Asset Management, L.P.) and Partner at Highland Capital Management, L.P.

He was also President, CEO and Trustee and/or Director of Pyxis/ Highland's NYSE-listed and 1940 Act registered funds operating under the Pyxis Funds and Highland Funds banners.

In addition to playing a critical role in the founding, launch, operation and expansion of Pyxis Funds (formerly Highland Funds), Joe was a Senior Portfolio Manager, Portfolio Manager and Portfolio Analyst for Highland Capital.

Mr. Dougherty was with Sandera Capital Management prior to his employment with Highland Capital in March of 1998.

Before this, Joe functioned as a Business Development Manager at Akzo Nobel and a Senior Accountant at Deloitte & Touche, LLP.

He earned an MBA from Southern Methodist University (SMU), and a BS in Accounting from Villanova University.

Mr. Dougherty (a Certified Public Accountant) can use the designation of a Chartered Financial Analyst.

# Experience

Pyxis Capital, L.P.
President
2008 - June 2012 (4 years)
Dallas, TX

Highland Capital Management, L.P.

Partner and Head of Retail Products 1998 - June 2012 (14 years)

AkzoNobel Business Developement Manager 1994 - 1996 (2 years)

Deloitte & Touche Middle Market Seervices 1992 - 1994 (2 years) Dallas, Tx

### Education

Southern Methodist University MBA, Finance · (1996 - 1998)

Villanova University
Bachelor of Science (B.S.), Accounting · (1988 - 1992)